<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Matt Makai</title><link href="http://www.letshackdc.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.letshackdc.com/feeds/blog-not-posted.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.letshackdc.com/</id><updated>2012-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Death By a Thousand Good Intentions</title><link href="http://www.letshackdc.com/death-by-thousand-good-intentions.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.letshackdc.com,2012-05-23:death-by-thousand-good-intentions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In all the government and large commerical environments I've worked in that
I can't seem to get much done compared to what I am capable of because I
am constantly facing blockers. I don't think anyone is deliberately trying
to stop me from developing quality software. But there's a whole lot of
good intentions flying around by people who don't know the full impact
of what they are talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examples&lt;/strong&gt;
If security creates The security guys down the hall that won't let a
server have an open HTTP connection? You're killing my ability to use
Python Package Index (PIP) installations. Is there a way around this so
I can use HTTPS instead? Sure. But it may take me hours to figure it out.
It'll be non-standard. I have to teach every developer around me why we
have to do it a way they've never seen before. This takes time. Time away
from me developing that great new functionality you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example. I need to use a virtual private connection to get on your
network? I have to use Citrix's terrible SmarTerm program instead of putty
or my usual Linux shell? I'm going to be slower because I'm not using
programs I'm comfortable with. Can I get the job done? Sure. But again this
takes time. Time away from developing actual software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example. I don't have access privileges to servers for two weeks
until after I arrive on my first day. Let's say I'm hypothetically getting
$125 an hour (I'm throwing this ballpark figure out - it's not what is
in the contract). 8 hrs a day * 10 days = 80 hours, 80 * 125 = $10000.
You just spent $10k getting little or nothing because I didn't have access.
I'm sure there's a good reason why security needed to manually approve
all those access privileges. Or not. But it cost $10k for that good reason.
Is no one watching those things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a thousand of these little good intentions by security, program
management, audit, legal, HR, etc etc, and you get virtually nothing.
It's amazing anything gets done at all in bureaucracies. All because everyone
is preventing great work from getting done due to &amp;quot;good intentions.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rant over.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>